Guide to the Yale Course Lectures Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Yale lectures, 1720-1980; Accession 19ND-A-394
  - Dunham, William H., History 146: British Constiution: Medieval and Modern, 871-1960, 1950-1967 (Box 102, Folder 436)
  - Dunham, William H., Feudal Goernment, 1949-1967 (Box 102, Folder 437)
  - Dunham, William H., History 190, 1952-1968 (Box 102, Folder 438)
  - Keller, Albert G, Anthropology and Science of Society, 1925-1926 (Box 102, Folder 439)
    Notetaker: Confrancesco, Harry W. (1926 Yale College)
  - Buchanan, James W., undated (Box 102, Folder 440)
  - Woodruff, Lorande l., Organic Evolution and Genetics, 1923-1924 (Box 102, Folder 441)
  - unknown, Anatomy, undated (Box 102, Folder 442)
  - Lanfear, Vincent W., 1923 (Box 103, Folder 443)
  - Adams, John C., undated (Box 103, Folder 444)
  - unknown, Ennyson and Browning, 1925-1926 (Box 103, Folder 445)
  - unknown, undated (Box 103, Folder 446)
    Subject: French
  - Rostovtzeff, Michael I., Ancient, Classical Civilization, 1925-1926 (Box 103, Folder 447)
  - Gabriel, Ralph H., American History, 1923-1924 (Box 103, Folder 448)
  - Mitchell, Sydney K., British Constitutional History, 1925-1926 (Box 103, Folder 449)
  - Turner, Edmund R., British Imperial History, 1924-1925 (Box 103, Folder 450)
  - unknown, European, Modern History, undated (Box 103, Folder 451)
  - Turner, Edmund R., History, Western Civilization, undated (Box 103, Folder 452)
  - Lipari, Angelo, Dante, undated (Box 104, Folder 453)
    Subject: Italian
  - Furniss, Edgar S., 1924 (Box 104, Folder 454)
  - Angier, Roswell P., Spencer, Liewellyn T., 1925-926 (Box 104, Folder 455)
  - Dwight, Timothy and others, "questions of debate before the Senior Class", 1801 (Box 104, Folder 456)
  - Dwight, Timothy, Theology ("exposition of Vincent's Catechism", 1802 (Box 104, Folder 457)
  - Bryant, R.C., logging, 1802 (Box 104, Folder 458)
  - Notes taken by Chauncy P. Williams, Jr. (1923 Yale College), 1920-1923 (Box 104, Folder 459-466)
  - Lecture notes of George McChain, 1846 (Box 104, Folder 467)
  - Student notes on lectures, 1953-1957 (Box 105, Folder 468-474)
  - Lecture notes on American diplomatic history course, taken by James M Banner, Jr., 1955-1956 (Box 105, Folder 475)
  - Margaret Meade's speech at the Commons Dining Hall, 2 audiotape (reel-to-reel), 1977 March 3 (Box 105, Folder 476)
  - Lecture presented at Sheffield Scientific School on concrete, 1901 (Box 105, Folder 477)
  - Lecture notes written by Timothy Dwight for courses in New Testament Greek and Exegesis, 1881 (Box 106, Folder 478)
  - Notes taken by John Marsh of the Chemical lectures of Benjamin Silliman, 1804 (Box 106, Folder 479)
  - Lectures given in the courses HYA 325a and 325b/725b and AMST 204b/804b and 325a by Jules Prown, Charles Montgomery, Margaretta Lovell and guests lecturers., undated; 11 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 107)
  - Lectures given in the courses HYA 325a and 325b/725b and AMST 204b/804b and 325a by Jules Prown, Charles Montgomery, Margaretta Lovell and guests lecturers., undated; 11 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 108)
  - Class of 1919 lecture notes, Circa 1915-1930 (Box 109)
- Notebook of George M. Bodman (1905 Yale College), circa 1905; Accession 19ND-A-474
  - Notebook on physics and British history, circa 1905 (Box 1)
- Class lecture notes of Everett Meeks for courses given in the School of Art, circa 1920-1950; Accession 1996-A-030
  - Class lecture notes of Everett Meeks for courses given in the School of Art, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1)
- Lecture Notes taken by David R. Coffin while a graduate student, 1940-1941; Accession 1998-A-025
  - Yale Prof.--Rostovzell(?) Classics 107(?), 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Professor Wind, Renaissance, Fall 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Professor Meeks, Italian Churches, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Professor Hamilton, Scientific Analysis, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Professor Focillan, Methodology, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Professor Focillan, Art d'Occident, Spring 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Professor Focillan, Early Medieval Art, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Professor Crosly, Byzantine Art, Fall 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Notebooks of Gilbert Banever (1934 BFA) from classes in the School of Fine Arts, 1932-1934; Accession 2001-A-150
  - History of Architecture notes, Professor E.V.Meeks, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Pictorial Art, Professor E. C. Taylor, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Pictorial Art Notebook, Professor E.C. Taylor, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 11)
  - Pictorial Art Notebook, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13)
  - Pictorial Art Notebook, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 14 - 15)
  - Introduction to Architecture (2 volumes), undated
- Writings for the course "Industrial Physiology. 63a. Sheffield Scientific School" by Professor Howard W. Haggard, 1924-1925; Accession 2002-A-159
  - Writings for the course "Industrial Physiology. 63a. Sheffield Scientific School" by Professor Howard W. Haggard, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
- Lecture notebooks of Thomas Frederick Davies, (1813 Yale College), Accession 2003-A-016
  - Lecture notebooks of Thomas Frederick Davies, Yale College Class of 1813, 1812-1813 (Box 1)
- Notes from classes by Franklin Farrel (1931 Yale College), Accession 2004-A-080
  - Notes from classes by Franklin Farrel, Class of 1931, circa 1928-1931 (Box 1)
- Lecture notes and teaching materials of professor Edmund S. Morgan, circa 1947-1986; Accession 2004-A-081
  - Lecture notes and teaching materials of professor Edmund S. Morgan, circa 1947-1986 (Box 1)
  - Lecture notes and teaching materials of professor Edmund S. Morgan, circa 1947-1986 (Box 2)
- Notebook on mechanical engineering by Henry M. Elliot (1911 Sheffield Scientic School), 1910; Accession 2005-A-070
  - Notebook on mechanical engineering by Henry M. Elliot, Class of 1911, Sheffield Scientic School, 1910 (Box 1)
- Notes of lectures given by Professor Arthur M. Wheeler, 1873; Accession 2005-A-078
  - Notes of lectures given by Professor Arthur M. Wheeler, 1873 (Box 1)
- Lecture notes taken by Charles G. Aschmann, Jr. (1941 Yale College), circa 1937-1941; Accession 2006-A-165
  - American Literature (English 39), circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Applied Physiology 63, circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art 10, circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chaucer, circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Classical Civilization 10, circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - English 10, circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - English 29, circa 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lecture notes of Henry A. Forchheimer (1883 Yale College) for "History of Philosophy" with Professor Ladd, Accession 2006-A-205
  - Notebook, 1883 (Box 1)
- Lecture notebooks of Walter Sidney Sanford (1900 Yale College), 1898-1899; Accession 2007-A-228
  - Ethics, 1898 Fall (Box 1)
  - Old Testament, 1898 Fall (Box 1)
  - English literature, 1899 (Box 1)
- Lecture notebook of William Henry Goodrich (1843 Yale College), 1844-1846; Accession 2011-A-049
  - Lecture notebook, 1844-1846 (Box 1)
- Lecture and reading notes, course syllabi, reading lists, and examinations for economic courses taken and taught by Shane Hunt (1963 PhD), 1957-1966; Accession 2014-A-052
  - Economics 100, Economic Theory (James Tobin) (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Economics 111a, Aggregative Economics (Arthur Okun) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Economics 130, Economic History (D.C. Coleman and Henry Broude) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Economics 171b, Taxation and Expenditure Policy (Challis Hall) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Economics 180b, International Economics (Lawrence Krause) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Economics 182, Postwar International Monetary Policies (Robert Triffin) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Economics 191a, Economic Development (Gerald Meier) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Economics 200, Reading Course in the History of Economic Thought (J.P. Miller) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Economics 100, 130a, 171b, and 180a, Midterm and/or final examinations (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Qualifying (comprehensive) examination of September 1959, in 4 parts (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Economics 39 (American Studies 40), The Structure of the American Economy (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Economics 118, Microeconomic Theory (for M.A. students) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Economics 119, (American Studies 175), The Sturcture of the American Economy (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Economics 39, 118, 119, Midterm and/or final examinations (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Lecture notes of John H. Bing (1960 Yale College) for American Studies Honor Program, 1958-1960; Accession 2017-A-032; Bing, John H.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of John H. Bing, 2016.
  - American Literary Expression before 1900, AS 81, Mr. Stone, syllabus, lecture notes, papers, and examinations, 1958 September-1959 May (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - American Literary Expression: The Twentieth Century, AS 87, Mr. Pearson, syllabus, lecture notes and papers, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Thought, AS 82, Mr. Strout, syllabus, lecture notes, papers, and examinations, 1958 September-1959 May (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - American Character and Institutions, AS 88, Mr. Chisholm and Mr. Wheeler, syllabus and lecture notes, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Recorded lectures of Professor Robert J. Fogelin, Circa 1970s; Accession 2018-A-0020
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Ph 120-4: Hobbes I (Box 1)
  - Ph 120-5: Hobbes II and Rawls I (Box 2)
  - Ph 120-6: Rawls II (Box 3)
  - Ph 120-16: Ethics, intro. lecture (Box 4)
  - Ph 120-17: Epicures (Box 5)
  - Ph 120-18: Epictetus (Box 6)
  - Ph 120-19: Bentham (Box 7)
  - Ph 120-20: Bentham/Mill (Box 8)
  - Ph 120-21: St. Thomas Aquinas (Box 9)
  - Ph 120-22: Rawls (Box 10)
  - Ph 120-23: Kant I (Box 11)
  - Ph 120-24: Kant II (Box 12)
  - Ph 120-25: Kant III (Box 13)
  - Ph 120-26: Kierkegaard (Box 14)
  - Ph 120-27: Sartre I and II (Box 15)
  - Ph 120-28: Nietzche I (Box 16)
  - Ph 120-29: Nietzche II (Box 17)
  - Ph 120-30: Hume I (Box 18)
  - Ph 120-31: Hume II (Box 19)
  - Ph 120-32: Ayer (Box 20)
  - Ph 120-33: Aristotle I (Box 21)
  - Ph 120-34: Aristotle II (Box 22)
  - Ph 120-35: Dewey I (Box 23)
  - Ph 120-36: Dewey II (Box 24)
- Lecture notebooks of Joseph B. Ullman (1933 Yale College), 1929-1933; Accession 2019-A-0018
  - International Relations, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Age of Johnson, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anatomy, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carmina translation to English, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Course lecture materials, examinations, papers, and admissions materials of Warner R. Schilling (1949 Yale College, 1951 MA, 1954 PhD), 1942-1951; Accession 2019-A-0033
  The course materials cover Schilling's undergraduate and graduate coursework at Yale University.
  - Admissions material
    - United States Government, State Procurement Office, 1942-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Course materials
    - Anthropology 10A, 10B, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Classical Civilization 21A, 21B, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Economics 10A, 10B, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Economics 38A, 42A, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - English 10A, 10B, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Foreign area studies, Modern Germany, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - German 20A, 20B, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Government 177, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Government 178A, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Government 178B, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - History 10B, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - History 57B, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - History 60A, 60B, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - History 61A, 61B, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - History 64A, 64B, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - History 171, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - History 187, circa 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - History 187, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - History 204A, 204B, circa 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - International Relations 110A, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - International Relations 110B, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - International Relations 116B, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - International Relations 118A, circa 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - International Relations 120A, 120B, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - International Relations 140, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - International Relations 201, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Logic, audited class, circa 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Math 12A, 12B, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Math homework, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Philosophy 12B, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Physics 10A, 10B, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Physics experiment books, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Political Science 10A, 10B, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Political Science 36A, 36B, 1945-1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Political Science 37A, 37B, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Psychology 20B, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Russian 25A, 25B, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 33B, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Papers and essays
      - Assorted undergraduate papers, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Demonstration Categories, circa 1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Graduate papers, circa 1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - The IR Rhetoric of Robert A. Taft & Taft and the Leites-Bolshevik, circa 1946-1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks
    - Anthropology 10A, 10B, 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Classical Civilization 21A, Political Institutions of Sparta, Athens, and Rome, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Classical Civilization 21B, Greek Political Philosophy, Aristotle-Plato, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Economics 10A, 10B, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - English and History 10A, 10B, rewrites, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Foreign area studies, Modern Germany, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Government 177, International Relations 110B, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - History 57A, Russia and Eastern Europe, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - History 57B, History of Russia, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - History 60A, European Diplomacy and Imperialism, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - History 60B, European Diplomacy and Imperialism, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - History 61A, Cultural Change in the Contemporary World, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - History 61B, Cultural Change in the Contemporary World, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - History 187, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - International Economics, circa 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - International Politics 37A, circa 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - International Relations 110A, 116B, 1947-1951 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - International Relations 118A, 178B, circa 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - International Relations 120A, 120B, Philosophy 113B, audited class, 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - International Relations 140, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - International Relations 178A, circa 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - International Relations 201A, 201B, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The labor movement, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Math 12A, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Philosophy, 12B, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Physics 10, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Political Science 37B, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Psychology 20, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Russian Foreign Policy 64B, 1946-1951 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 33B, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Course notes, examinations, and papers of Mark Hubert Curtis (1942 Yale College, 1953 PhD), 1939-1948; Accession 2019-A-0034
  - Course materials
    - Book report on Pilgrim's Way and essay notes, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ecumenical Institute, World's Student Christian Federation, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Exam books, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Final examination instructions, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - History 2a, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - History 11, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - History 126, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - History 136, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - History 140, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - History 141 essay, Puritanism in the Universities, 1559-1572, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - History 180, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Philosophy 10, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notebooks
    - English 20, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - English 28, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Government 48, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - History 21, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - History 44, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Course materials and notebooks of Susan P. Casteras in Art History (1973 MA, 1975 MPhil, 1977 PhD), 1971-1989; Accession 2019-M-0035
  - Course materials
    - Eakins, Susan Macdowell, exhibition material and files, 1972-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - Student papers
      - Angelica Kauffman and her Influence on Benjamin West, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Caravaggio and the Supper at Emmaus: An Assessment, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Reginald Marsh's Coney Island Beach: An Analysis, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Susan Macdowell Eakins: The Career She Never Gave Up, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Syllabi and bibliographies, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Art history course notebooks
    - A, Professor Michael Kitson, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - B, Professor Theodore Stebbins, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 55a, Professor George Kubler, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 60b, German painting, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 200a, Professor Egbert Haverkamp-Begemann, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 242a, Professor Charles Seymour Jr., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 249a, Professor Wolfgang Stechow, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 252a, Professor George Hersey, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 254a, Professor Theodore Stebbins, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 393a, Professor John Wilmerding, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - British art, Professor Jules Prown, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Color and color theory, Professor Robert Herbert, circa 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Methods I, Professor Egbert Haverkamp-Begemann, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Museums, Professor Alan Shestack, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Space in art, Professor Ann Hanson, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Women in America, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)